http://www.mtv.co.uk/legal/privacy-policy

Updated: 4 December 2019
At Viacom International Media Networks UK Limited (“VIMN UK”), we take your privacy seriously and are committed to ensuring that we protect the information you entrust to us. We created this Privacy Policy to tell you what personal information VIMN UK collects about you, how we use, store and share it, and your rights and choices concerning that information. This Privacy Policy applies to all information about you that we collect, whether you are visiting our websites, using one of our mobile apps or other products or services, or otherwise interacting with us, such as by attending a live event, or contacting customer service. This policy collectively refers to these touchpoints as the “Services.” While some of the information we describe here is technical, our goal is to make this policy straightforward, so please contact us if you have any questions.
We will change this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we make changes, we will revise the date at the top of the policy and, in some cases, will notify you through the Services, such as via our homepage, email, or other communication.
Personal Information We Collect
In this section, we explain what personal information we collect about you and how we collect it.
Information You Provide
You can use most of our Services without actively submitting any information about yourself, but you may choose to provide us with personal information through the Services. In particular:
If you choose to register an account with us, we will collect your name and email address
If you choose to purchase a product, we will collect payment information
If you choose to receive text or WhatsApp messages from us, we will collect your mobile phone number
If you choose to participate in any contests, promotions, or market research surveys we sponsor, we will collect information such as your postal address, phone number, or information about your interests
If you choose to post content or communicate with us or with others on a public platform or through user support, we will collect the information you provide in those posting
Automatically Collected Information
When you access our Services online, for example by visiting our websites or using our mobile apps, we automatically collect information about your use of the Services, such as the time of your visit and the pages or content you viewed. We also receive and collect technical information about your device and software, including the type of device, operating system and version, mobile network information, IP address (a unique number used to identify a device on the internet), mobile device advertising identifier (a resettable identifier that is assigned to your mobile device by your operating system provider, such as Apple or Google) or other device identifier, the page you visited before visiting our website, and crash data.
Cookies
We and our advertising and analytics service providers use cookies, which are small text files that help store user preferences and activity, and similar technologies such as web beacons, pixels, and ad tags to recognise you when you visit our Services, and to collect information such as the number of visits, which features or pages are popular, measurements about the advertising campaign’s success, and other information about your browsing activities. This allows us to ensure our Services are functioning properly, to improve the Services, and to provide and measure advertisements. For more information about cookies and the choices you have regarding the use of them through our Services, please visit our Cookie Policy.
Information from Third Parties
We may offer you the ability to log into the Services with your credentials from another site or service, such as Facebook or Google. If you chose to login or register in this manner, the third-party service will provide us with access to information about you, such as your name, basic profile information, and friends list, in accordance with your privacy settings on that service.
Social Sharing
The Services may give you the option to share with others on social media platforms, such as Facebook or Twitter. When you share in this manner, the privacy practices of the social media platform control who has access to your information and how it is treated by the social media platform. Please consult the privacy policies of any social media platform to which you share information in this manner to learn about the social media platform’s data practices.
Please note that information that cannot be linked back to you (such as aggregated data) is not considered personal information under this Policy.
Use of Information
We use the personal information for the following purposes:
Manage your account
Enable you to participate in public platforms or other interactive features of the Services
Fulfill orders you have placed
Respond to customer service requests
Send promotional messages and newsletters you request
Target advertisements to you both on and off of our Services
Analyse traffic and user activities on our Services, identifying popular areas or features, and optimising and personalising the Services
Provide, maintain, and improve our Services, as well as to develop new content and features
Protect the rights and property of VIMN UK and others, including to detect, investigate, and prevent fraud and other illegal activities and to enforce our agreements
Data Storage
We store the personal information we collect for as long as is necessary for the purpose(s) for which we originally collected it. For example, if you register for an account with us, we will generally maintain your account information as long as needed to service your account. We may also retain personal information as required by law.
Disclosure of Your Personal Information
We will not disclose your personal information to any unrelated third parties unless we have your consent to do so, with the exceptions we mention here:
With service providers who provide services to us under a contract and are required to keep the personal information confidential
If reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation, or compulsory process (for example, to respond to a subpoena)
If we conclude your actions violate our user agreements or policies, or to protect the rights, property or safety of VIMN UK or others
In connection with a merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business, provided that the receiving party agrees to protect personal information in accordance with the commitments of this policy and applicable law
With companies within the Viacom corporate family
We share personal information that does not directly identify you but that identifies your device through third-party cookies and similar technologies on our website and in our apps, to enable those third parties to provide us with analytics and advertising services. Those companies collect information from our website or apps such as cookie identifiers, device identifiers, IP address, as well as information about your web viewing or app usage activity off of the Services. To learn more about how this information can be used for serving interest-based advertising, how VIMN UK uses these services, and for links to these third parties’ privacy policies, please visit our Cookie Policy.
Data Transfers
We and our service providers transfer your personal information to, or store or access it in, other countries where the laws may not provide levels of protection for your personal information equivalent the protection provided by the laws of the European Union. When we do this, we take steps to ensure that your personal information receives an appropriate level of protection through contractual requirements imposed on the recipient of the information (you can obtain a copy of these clauses by contacting us).
Legal Basis for Processing
We will only collect, store, or otherwise process your personal information in the following situations:
When we have your consent to do so. For example, if you opt in to receive promotional emails. You can withdraw your consent at any time as described below or directly through the Services.
We need to use your personal information to perform our responsibilities under our contract with you (e.g., providing the products or services you have requested).
We have a legitimate interest in processing your personal information. For example, we may process your personal information to communicate with you about our Services; and to provide, secure, and improve our Services.
We are required by law to process the information.
Your Rights and Choices
You have the right to access the personal information we hold about you and to ask us to correct, erase, or, in some situations, transfer it to another provider. You may also have the right to withdraw your consent to processing, object to, or request that we limit or restrict certain processing of your personal information as described below.
Access and Deletion Requests
You can also update, correct, or delete information we have about you or close your account by contacting us at DataPrivacyRights@viacom.com with the subject line “Privacy Rights”. When necessary to identify you, we will request that you give proof of your identity or require more information from you that is necessary to handle your request.
Emails, Text Messages, and WhatsApp Messages
You can opt out of receiving promotional emails, text messages, or WhatsApp messages by following the instructions in those messages. If you opt out of receiving promotional emails from us, we may still send you non-promotional emails.
Mobile push notifications
When you consent, we may send promotional and non-promotional push notifications or alerts to your mobile device. You can deactivate these messages at any time by changing the notification settings on your mobile device.
Cookies and similar technologies
For information about the choices you have regarding our use of cookies, including how to block cookies or withdraw consent to certain types of cookies and other similar technologies, please visit our Cookie Policy.
Questions or complaints
If you have a question about our Privacy Policy, data practices or the choices available to you, please contact us using the information below. If we are not able to address your concern and you are a resident of the EEA, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Authority where you live, work, or where the issue took place. For contact details of your local Data Protection Authority, please see http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm.
Contact Us
We are happy to answer your questions about our Privacy Policy and data practices. You may also contact us to exercise your rights as discussed in this Privacy Policy.
Viacom International Media Networks UK Limited
Data Protection OfficerDataPrivacyRights@viacom.com
17-29 Hawley Crescent, London, NW1 8TT
Hit us with some keywords!
